So let's just go through some examples and I'm going to include less than here.
因此，让我们通过一些示例，我将包括比这里更少的示例。
We've been talking about more than and her right.
我们一直在谈论超过和她的权利。
But we can include less a..
但是我们可以少包含一个..
Then as well.
然后也是。
And it follows the same basic rules.
它遵循相同的基本规则。
If you wanted to say more beautiful then you could also say less beautiful then.
如果你想说更漂亮，那么你也可以说不那么漂亮。
But what if we want to then say the opposite with R.
但是，如果我们想用 R 说相反的话怎么办。
Well then you have to change the adjective if you want to say less beautiful then it might be better
那么你必须改变形容词如果你想说不那么漂亮那么它可能会更好
if you just say uglier than ugly ugly or uglier than right.
如果你只是说丑比丑丑或丑比正确。
It's the same thing less beautiful then may be the same as uglier then.
不那么漂亮的东西可能和那么丑陋的东西一样。
So it follows the same basic rules same basic rules we just use less instead of more.
所以它遵循相同的基本规则相同的基本规则，我们只是使用更少而不是更多。
Or choose an opposite adjective an opposite adjective and had e r let's go through some basic examples.
或者选择一个相反的形容词和一个相反的形容词，让我们来看看一些基本的例子。
Is there anything more beautiful than a sunset.
有什么比夕阳更美的。
Is there anything more beautiful than a sunset sunset is when the sun goes down.
有什么比夕阳西下的夕阳更美的呢。
This is a rhetorical question.
这是一个反问。
That means you don't need to answer the question.
这意味着你不需要回答这个问题。
I'm just saying it.
我只是说。
Is there anything more beautiful than than a sunset.
有什么比夕阳更美的呢。
Learning English is more interesting than I thought.
学习英语比我想象的更有趣。
So here we're not comparing two things exactly right.
所以在这里我们并没有完全正确地比较两件事。
More interesting than I thought were comparing sort of an opinion about something now to an opinion
比我想象的更有趣的是将现在对某事的某种观点与一种观点进行比较
about something in the past like me now and me in the past.
关于过去的事情，比如现在的我和过去的我。
This as I sort of see it and as I experience it is much more interesting than me back then and how I
这在我看来和我所经历的那样比当时的我更有趣，以及我是如何
felt about it then learning English.
感觉它然后学习英语。
So this is sort of like the noun.
所以这有点像名词。
Learning English is more interesting than I thought.
学习英语比我想象的更有趣。
This is an hour.
这是一个小时。
It doesn't say Mo's hit my r's sometimes look like S's.
并不是说 Mo 击中我的 r 有时看起来像 S。
This hospital is much less professional than my usual one.
这家医院比我平时的专业少得多。
We could say usual hospital but it's not necessary because the last thing that we said Well at least
我们可以说通常的医院，但这没有必要，因为我们说的最后一件事至少是
the topic the thing we're talking about is hospital.
我们谈论的话题是医院。
And so when we say one we know it's about hospital then my usual hospital than my usual one.
所以当我们说一个我们知道这是关于医院的时候，我通常的医院比我通常的医院。
So one can often replace a noun.
所以经常可以代替名词。
OK.
好的。
Now here's an interesting exception where we have a special word that we can use which is the opposite
现在这是一个有趣的例外，我们可以使用一个特殊的词，它是相反的
of better.
的更好。
All right.
好的。
If this hospital is better this hospital is better than my usual one.
如果这家医院好的话，这家医院就比我平时的好。
That's easy right.
这很容易对。
E.R. You have a special word we don't say more good.
E.R. 你有一个特殊的词，我们不会说更好。
We don't say more better we just say better could say my usual hospital is better than this one.
我们不说更好，我们只是说更好，可以说我通常的医院比这家更好。
So one simple way to express the opposite is to just reverse the order of the things instead of saying
所以表达相反的一种简单方法是颠倒事物的顺序而不是说
this hospital is less professional.
这家医院不太专业。
Right.
正确的。
We could just say my usual hospital is much better than this one.
我们只能说我平常的医院比这家好得多。
OK.
好的。
Or much more professional.
或者更专业。
Of course that's also something we could do.
当然这也是我们可以做的。
But what if we want to say the same thing and instead we want to use E.R..
但是，如果我们想说同样的话，而我们想使用 E.R.。
Well here is where we have a special exception.
好吧，这是我们有一个特殊例外的地方。
We have this special word worse worse as a special one this hospital is much worse is much worse than
我们有这个特殊的词更糟糕作为一个特殊的医院更糟糕的是比
my usual one is much worse than my usual one.
我平常的比我平常的要差得多。
So that's the opposite word to use and it's a special case we don't add E.R. We don't say worser.
所以这是使用相反的词，这是一个特殊情况，我们不添加 E.R. 我们不说更糟。
Couple more examples you're cooler than you were last year.
再举几个例子，你比去年更酷。
You're cooler than you were last year.
你比去年更酷了。
So again this is not two things but it kind of is.
所以这又不是两个薄gs 但它有点像。
Except it's two people but it's not really two people although it kind of is because it's about two
除了是两个人，但它不是真正的两个人，虽然这有点是因为它大约是两个人
different times.
不同的时间。
This is person A maybe in two thousand and nine and this is person A in two thousand and ten.
这可能是 2009 年的 A 人，而这是 2000 年的 A 人。
I don't know why those years it's not this year.
我不知道为什么那些年不是今年。
So we could say you're cooler than you were last year.
所以我们可以说你比去年更酷。
That means now is more cool than 2009.
这意味着现在比 2009 年更酷。
If we wanted to switch that around then we could say in 2009 you weren't as cool as you are this year
如果我们想改变这一点，那么我们可以说 2009 年你没有今年那么酷
and we'll talk about that.
我们会谈到这一点。
Not as cool as in a moment.
没有一瞬间那么酷。
You're better than me at ping pong.
你打乒乓球比我好。
I'm worse than you at ping pong.
我的乒乓球比你差。
OK now if we wanted to make it another word and we wanted to use more or less we could use skilled.
好的，如果我们想换个词，并且我们想或多或少地使用，我们可以使用熟练的。
For example you're more skilled than me at ping pong.
比如你打乒乓球比我熟练。
So let's go into a couple other types of comparison before we get into some deeper examples.
因此，在我们进入一些更深层次的例子之前，让我们先来看看其他类型的比较。